Guide to the Evelyn L. Pugh papers, 1959-1983
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Evelyn L. Pugh papers
1959-1983
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Evelyn Littleton Pugh, 1930-1987
C0012
9 linear feet (24 boxes)
Materials in the collection support the study of John Stuart Mill and women's rights. They include the following: manuscript copy of "John Stuart Mill and Half the Human Race" by Evelyn L. Pugh; Pugh's master's thesis entitled: "The Socialist Party in the Election of 1932" (1959); her dissertation "John Stuart Mill in America: The Early Impact, 1843-1873"(1966); scholarly publications by Pugh; course syllabi and course materials; bibliographic lists and bibliographic and note card files.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Robert E. Pugh in 1989.
Biographical Information
Evelyn L. Pugh was a faculty member in the Department of History at George Mason University from 1965 to 1987, specializing in the study of John Stuart Mill and women's rights.
Scope and Content
Materials in the collection support the study of Mill and women's rights. They include the following: manuscript copy of "John Stuart Mill and Half the Human Race" by Evelyn L. Pugh; Pugh's master's thesis entitled: "The Socialist Party in the Election of 1932" (1959); her dissertation "John Stuart Mill in America: The Early Impact, 1843-1873"(1966); scholarly publications by Pugh; course syllabi and course materials; bibliographic lists and bibliographic and note card files.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by subject.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the papers of GMU history professor Roy Rosenzweig.
Index Terms
Persons:
Mill, John Stuart, 1806-1873.; Pugh, Evelyn Littleton, 1930-1987.
Subjects:
Women's rights--Europe--History--19th century.; Women's rights--United States--History--19th century.
Contents List
- Evelyn L. Pugh papers
  - University Press Letters (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Working Outline (Evelyn Pugh) (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Working Outline by Chapters (Dick O'Keeffe) (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Manuscript (A-J Chapters) (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - Manuscript (K-P Chapters) (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - Manuscript (Q-R Chapters) (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - Manuscript (John Stuart Mill and the Women's Question in Parliament, 1865-68) (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - Manuscript and notes on subjection of women in England (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - Jailed for Freedom, 1990 (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - Pugh, Evelyn L. "John Stuart Mill in America: The Early Impact 1843-73". Ph. D. dissertation, The American University, 1966, v.1 (Folder 1, Box 2)
  - Pugh, Evelyn L. "John Stuart Mill in America: The Early Impact 1843-73". Ph.D. dissertation, The American University, 1966, v.2 (Folder 2, Box 2)
  - Pugh, Evelyn L. "The Socialist Party in the Election of 1932." Master's thesis, Duke University, 1959 (Folder 3, Box 2)
  - Eulogy (Folder 4, Box 2)
  - Publication: Pugh, Evelyn L. "Politics and Light Verse: Another Look at J.S. Mill." The Mill Newsletter, v.XII., no.2, 1977 (Folder 1, Box 3)
  - Publication: Pugh, Evelyn L. "The First Woman Candidate for Parliament: Helen Taylor and the Election of 1885." International Journal of Women's Studies, v.1, no.4, July/August 1978 (Folder 2, Box 3)
  - Publication: Pugh, Evelyn L. "John Stuart Mill, Harriet Taylor, and Women's Rights in America, 1850-73." Canadian Journal of History, v.XII., no.3, December 1978 (Folder 3, Box 3)
  - Publication: Pugh, Evelyn L. "Suffragette Prisoners at the Occoquan Workhouse." Northern Virginia Heritage, v.I, no.3, October 1979 (Folder 4, Box 3)
  - Publication: Pugh, Evelyn L. "Women and Slavery: Julia Gardiner Tyler and Duchess of Sutherland." The Virginia Magazine of History and Biography, v.88. no.2, April 1980 (Folder 5, Box 3)
  - Publication: Pugh, Evelyn L. "John Stuart Mill and the Women's Question in Parliament, 1865-1868." The Historian, v. XLII, May 1980 (Folder 6, Box 3)
  - Publication: Pugh, Evelyn L."J.S. Mill's Autobiography and the Hyde park Riots." Research Studies, v.50, no.1, March 1982 (Folder 7, Box 3)
  - Publication: Pugh, Evelyn L. "Florence Nightingale and J.S. Mill Debate Women's Rights." Journal of British Studies, v.XXI, no.2, Spring 1982 (Folder 8, Box 3)
  - Presentations (see resume for the list) (Folder 9, Box 3)
  - Resume (Folder 1, Box 4)
  - Promotion and Salary (Folder 2, Box 4)
  - Faculty Annual Reviews (Folder 3, Box 4)
  - Advising (Folder 4, Box 4)
  - Committees (Folder 5, Box 4)
  - Consulting (Folder 6, Box 4)
  - Syllabus (Folder 7, Box 4)
  - Research Grants and Leaves (Folder 8, Box 4)
  - Correspondence (Folder 9, Box 4)
  - Correspondence (Folder 10, Box 4)
  - Correspondence- Panels, Programs, Presentations (Folder 11, Box 4)
  - Correspondence- Publications (Folder 12, Box 4)
  - Correspondence- Recommendations (Folder 13, Box 4)
  - Correspondence- Reviews and Evaluations (Folder 14, Box 4)
  - Reviews of Proposed Books (Folder 15, Box 4)
  - Virginia Women's Cultural History Project (Folder 16, Box 4)
  - Women Historians (Folder 17, Box 4)
  - Telephone List (Folder 18, Box 4)
  - Orders (Folder 19, Box 4)
  - Current Outline (Folder 1, Box 5)
  - Hamilton, Margaret, "Opposition to Woman Suffrage in England: 1865-1884 A Case Study of a Counter movement." Victorian Institute Journal, v.4, 1975 (Folder 2, Box 5)
  - "The Suppressed Sex", Westminster Review, v. XXXIV, October 1968 (Folder 3, Box 5)
  - Women and Music (Folder 4, Box 5)
  - Pike, Luke Owen. "A History of Crime in England." (Folder 5, Box 5)
  - Voting (Robert Peel) (Folder 6, Box 5)
  - McGregor, Oliver R. "Divorce in England." (Folder 7, Box 5)
  - Illustrations (Folder 8, Box 5)
  - Viner, Jacob "Bentham and Mill: The Unitarian Background." From the Long View and the Short (Folder 9, Box 5)
  - The Subjection of Women (Folder 10, Box 5)
  - Robertson, John and Stevenson, Pierce "Criticism on Women." Western Review, v. XXXII, April 1839 (Folder 11, Box 5)
  - Russian Translation (Folder 12, Box 5)
  - Sovremennik(Petersburg), Nov. 1860, no.s., v.84, pp.221-50 (Folder 13, Box 5)
  - Kowalewski, David "Politics and Emotion in the Thought of John Stuart Mill" Journal of Psychohistory, v.7, Spring 1980 (Folder 14, Box 5)
  - JSM-Russia- Women's Rights (Folder 15, Box 5)
  - JSM- Japan- Women's Rights (Folder 16, Box 5)
  - "The Subjection of Women" introduction to Russian edition, 1861 (Folder 17, Box 5)
  - Scott, Firor "Women's Perspective on the Patriarchy in the 1850s." Journal of American History, v.LXI, June 1974 (Folder 18, Box 5)
  - Comments on JSM and the Objection of Women in the Nation, 1870 (Folder 19, Box 5)
  - Wheeler, Anna Doyle, in Biographical Dictionary of Modern British Radicals (Folder 20, Box 5)
  - Schneidermeyer, Wilma "JSM's Principle of Liberty and Legislative Reality" in Journal of Human Relations, v.20, 1972 (Folder 21, Box 5)
  - Harrison, Frederick. "JSM" (Folder 22, Box 5)
  - Women's Suffrage (Folder 23, Box 5)
  - Parkman, Francis (Folder 24, Box 5)
  - Minorities (Folder 25, Box 5)
  - Municipal Government Bill (Folder 26, Box 5)
  - JSM (Folder 27, Box 5)
  - Jamaica (Folder 28, Box 5)
  - Free Trade (Folder 29, Box 5)
  - Irish Question (Folder 30, Box 5)
  - General Election, 1968 (Folder 31, Box 5)
  - 1968 Election Results (Folder 32, Box 5)
  - 1968 Election Chedwsck [Bonheur] (Folder 33, Box 5)
  - Women in British Parliamentary Elections(Current) (Folder 34, Box 5)
  - Parliament 1867 (Folder 35, Box 5)
  - Showalter's Article on Women (Folder 36, Box 5)
  - Bertrand Russell on Women (Folder 37, Box 5)
  - Goldstein, Leslie."Mill, Marx, and Women's Liberation." (Folder 1, Box 6)
  - Fawcett Library (Folder 2, Box 6)
  - Stone, Olive M. "Recent Developments in Family Law in British Common Law Jurisdictions."Columbia Law Review, v.67, November 1967 (Folder 3, Box 6)
  - "Property of Married Women." Westminster Review, October 1868 (Folder 4, Box 6)
  - Paulson, Ross Evans."Women's Suffrage and Prohibition: A Comparative Study of Equality and Social Control." (Folder 5, Box 6)
  - Meliora: A Quarterly Review of Social Science (Folder 6, Box 6)
  - Ethelmer, E. "Feminism." Westminster Review, CIL (149), 1898 (Folder 7, Box 6)
  - Pankhurst, R."The Right of Women to Vote Under the Reform Act, 1867." Fortnightly Review, v.10, no.4, September 1968 (Folder 8, Box 6)
  - "The New Law of Divorce." English Women's Journal, v.1, May 1858 (Folder 9, Box 6)
  - Shattock, Joanne and Michael Wolff. "The Victorian Periodical Press: Samplings and Soundings." (Folder 10, Box 6)
  - JSM- Speech at Edinburgh, 1871. Brignt, Jacob- Speech at Edinburgh, 1870 (Folder 11, Box 6)
  - Stanton, Theodore. "The Women Question in Europe." Kemnitz, Thomas M."Nineteenth Century English History:Materials for Teaching and Study." Stites, Richard."M.L. Mikhailov and the Emergence of the Woman Question in Russia." (Folder 12, Box 6)
  - Stillinger, Jack. "Who Wrote J.S. Mill's Autobiography?" Victorian Studies, v.27, no.1, Autumn 1983 (Folder 13, Box 6)
  - Altman, Elizabeth C. "The Philosophical Bases of Feminism: The Feminist Doctrines of the Saint-Simonians and Charles Fourier." (Folder 14, Box 6)
  - The Ladies Gallery (Folder 15, Box 6)
  - Clarke, M.L. "George Grote: A Biography."(For section on early H. Taylor) (Folder 16, Box 6)
  - Johnson, L.G. "General T. Perronet Thompson 1783-1869: His Military, Literary and Political Campaigns." (Folder 17, Box 6)
  - Women: ELP Talk (Folder 18, Box 6)
  - The Gerrutsen Collection on Women's History, 1543-1945 (Folder 19, Box 6)
  - Kansas (Folder 20, Box 6)
  - Chandor, John."Marriage- Georgian Style." Horizon, v.16, Autumn 1974 (Folder 21, Box 6)
  - Violence (Folder 22, Box 6)
  - [JSM and NEO-Malthusianism] (Folder 1, Box 7)
  - Pym, Horace, Journals of Caroline Fox (Folder 2, Box 7)
  - Harrison, Brain."Separate Spheres." (Folder 3, Box 7)
  - Power, Susan M."Democracy, Representation and John Stuart Mill." Susguchanne University Studies, v.VII, June 1965 (Folder 4, Box 7)
  - JSM Letters (Folder 5, Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 6, Box 7)
  - Spiegelberg, Herbert."Accident of Birth: A Non-Utilitarian Motif in Mill's Philosophy."Journal of the History of Ideas, v.XXII, Oct.-Dec. 1961 (Folder 7, Box 7)
  - Hughes, Patricia."The Reality Versus the Ideal: J.S. Mill's Treatment of Women, Workers, and Private Property." Canadian Journal of Political Science, v.2, September 1979 (Folder 8, Box 7)
  - Shorter, Edward. "Female Emancipation, Birth Control, and Fertility in European History." AHR, v.78, n.3, June 1973 (Folder 9, Box 7)
  - Broadhurst, Thomas." Advice to Young Ladies on the Improvement of the Mind." Edinburg Review, v.15 (Folder 10, Box 7)
  - Reeve, Henry."Autobiography of JSM." Edinburgh Review, v.139, January 1874. J.F. Stephen and the Crisis of Victorian Thought."Liberty, Equality, Fraternity." (Folder 11, Box 7)
  - Austin, Sarah. "Madame Recamier." Fraser's Magazine, v.40, September 1849 (Folder 12, Box 7)
  - Holyoke, George Jacob. "JSM As Some of the Working Classes Knew Him." (Folder 13, Box 7)
  - Amberley, Lord (Folder 14, Box 7)
  - Yale Manuscripts (Folder 15, Box 7)
  - Maison, Margaret."Insignificant Objects of Desire." The Listener, v.86, July 1971 (Folder 16, Box 7)
  - Kinzer, Bruce L."J.S. Mill and the Problem of Party." Journal of British Studies, v.XXI, Fall 1981 (Folder 17, Box 7)
  - Letter from London School of Economics (Folder 18, Box 7)
  - Debates (Folder 19, Box 7)
  - Legal Bibliography on Marriage and Divorce (Folder 20, Box 7)
  - Helps, Sir Arthur."Women in Education." Friends in Council (Folder 21, Box 7)
  - Miller, P.J. "Women's Education, Self-Improvement and Social Mobility- A Late Eighteenth Century Debate." British Journal of Educational Studies, v.20, no.3, October 1972 (Folder 22, Box 7)
  - Education (Folder 23, Box 7)
  - Robson, J.M."Bibliography, Research Materials, and Editions" and "A Note on Mill Bibliography." (Folder 24, Box 7)
  - Broadhurst, Thomas."Advice to Young Ladies on the Improvement of the Mind" in Sidney Smith. Memories of Alfieri. Edinburg Review, v.XV, January 1810 (Folder 25, Box 7)
  - Thompson, Dorothy."Women and Nineteenth Century Radical Politics: A Lost Dimension." (Folder 26, Box 7)
  - Alexander, Sally."Women's Work in Nineteenth Century London: A Study of the Years 1820-50." (Folder 27, Box 7)
  - Price, Richard."The Making of Working-Class History." Victorian Studies, v.20, Autumn 1976 (Folder 28, Box 7)
  - Norton, Caroline.Items from examiner; her reply to British and Foreign Review; general article on "Custody of Infants." (Folder 29, Box 7)
  - Stone, Olive M. "The Status of Women in Great Britain." American Journal of Comparative Law, Fall 1922 (Folder 30, Box 7)
  - JSM and Westminster Review (Folder 31, Box 7)
  - Holdsmith- History of English Law, v.5 (Folder 32, Box 7)
  - Margaret, Walters (Folder 1, Box 9)
  - Crane, [Grane] - A Century of Family Law (Folder 2, Box 9)
  - [Women's Work] and Correspondence with JSM (Folder 3, Box 9)
  - History of Women's Suffrage, v.2 (Folder 4, Box 9)
  - Radcliffe College (Folder 5, Box 9)
  - Sherwood Forest (Folder 6, Box 9)
  - JSM and Comte (Folder 7, Box 9)
  - Simon, Walter M.- European Positivism in the 19th Century (Folder 8, Box 9)
  - Thompson, William (Folder 9, Box 9)
  - Davies, Emily- Thoughts on Same Questions Relating to Women, 1860-1908 (Suffrage Chapter) (Folder 10, Box 9)
  - Pankhurst, Richard K.P.-Fourierism in Britain (Folder 11, Box 9)
  - Law Reports (Folder 12, Box 9)
  - Ten, C.L.- Mill and Liberty (Folder 13, Box 9)
  - Critique of Subjection of Women. Owen, Harold-Women Adrift (Folder 14, Box 9)
  - "State of Historical Science in France." British and Foreign Review, 1844 (Folder 15, Box 9)
  - JSM-Plagiarism (Folder 16, Box 9)
  - Collini, Stefan."Liberalism and the Legacy of Mill." The Historical Journal, v.20, no.1, 1977 (Folder 17, Box 9)
  - Mattick, Barbara. A Response to Industrialization (Senior Seminer paper, Spring 1976) (Folder 18, Box 9)
  - "JSM and the English Women's Movement." Historical Studies: Australian and New Zealand, v.18, April 1978 (Folder 19, Box 9)
  - Women's Trade Union Leage- Annual Report, 1908-1919 (Folder 1, Box 10)
  - Annie Besart on General Gordon (Folder 2, Box 10)
  - [Annie Besart] (Folder 3, Box 10)
  - Annie Besart- Reviews (Folder 4, Box 10)
  - Annie Besart on George Elliot and Woman's Question (Folder 5, Box 10)
  - National Reformer- Political Economy in 1886- Capital and Lloyd George (Folder 6, Box 10)
  - Increased Employment of Women During War(WW I) (Folder 7, Box 10)
  - Central Committee on Women's Employment(Unemployment because of war) (Folder 8, Box 10)
  - Women in Non-Munition Factories(WW I) (Folder 9, Box 10)
  - Women in American Revolution (Folder 10, Box 10)
  - "Corn and Flowers: The Social and Cultural Activities of the Women's Trade Union League." Women's Union Journal (Folder 11, Box 10)
  - Flora MacDonald (Folder 12, Box 10)
  - Poetry and first draft of article (Folder 13, Box 10)
  - Marriage Reform- Letter From Cairnes to JSM: Marriage Settlements (Folder 14, Box 10)
  - Women's Periodicals: The English Women's Journal, Victorian Periodicals, The Victoria Magazine, and Newsletter (Folder 15, Box 10)
  - Thompson, William."Inquiry into the Principles of Distribution of Wealth." (Folder 16, Box 10)
  - Pankhurst, Richard: William Thompson and Alice Wheeter (Folder 17, Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous- Alice(Lewis Caroll), Disputed Authorship, etc (Folder 18, Box 10)
  - Women and Poor Laws (Folder 19, Box 10)
  - Brandes (Folder 20, Box 10)
  - Krenis, Lee."Authorithy and Rebellion in Victorian Autobiography." (Folder 21, Box 10)
  - Translations of "Subjection of Women" (Folder 22, Box 10)
  - Charles Kingsley and JSM on Women's Rights (Folder 23, Box 10)
  - Divorce (Folder 24, Box 10)
  - [Dilke, C.]- Cosmopolis (Folder 25, Box 10)
  - Rees, J.C."A Phase in the Development of Mill's Ideas on Liberty." Political Studies (Folder 26, Box 10)
  - Schneidermeyer, Wilma."John Stuart Mill's Principle of Liberty and Legislative Reality." Journal of Human Relations, 1972 (Folder 27, Box 10)
  - Taylor, Barbara- The Woman-Power (Folder 28, Box 10)
  - McCabe, George."Life and Letters of George Jacob Holyoke", "History of Cooperation", and "First Plan of the Woman's Rights Agitation." (Folder 29, Box 10)
  - Women's Suffrage- Australia (Folder 30, Box 10)
  - Philo, Familiar."Law of Husband and Wife." (Folder 31, Box 10)
  - JSM letters from university college already in printed volumes (Folder 1, Box 11)
  - The Cave of Adullam and Parliamentary Reform (Folder 2, Box 11)
  - Married Women's Property Bill (Folder 3, Box 11)
  - Parliament,1866-Primarily Women- Lydic Beker's article (Folder 4, Box 11)
  - First draft of paper on violence (Folder 5, Box 11)
  - Ideas for Columns (Folder 6, Box 11)
  - Copy of dissertation proposed (Folder 7, Box 11)
  - Du Bois, Ellen. "The Radicalism of the Woman Suffrage Movement..." (Folder 8, Box 11)
  - Journals (Folder 9, Box 11)
  - Notes for JSM and women in the U.S (Folder 10, Box 11)
  - Rees, J.C. " A Re-reading of Mill on Liberty." Political Studies, v.VIII, no.2, 1960 (Folder 11, Box 11)
  - Articles on women from National Reformer (Folder 12, Box 11)
  - Van Halthoon, F.L. "Road to Utopic: A Study of JSM's Social Thoughts." 1971 (Folder 13, Box 11)
  - First draft of JSM and Subjection of Women (Folder 14, Box 11)
  - Talk on Miss. Nightingale (Folder 15, Box 11)
  - Material on working women (Folder 16, Box 11)
  - Tingsten, Herbert. "Victoria and the Victorians." (Folder 17, Box 11)
  - Pugh, Evelyn. " JSM, Harriet Taylor, and Women's Rights in America, 1850-1873." Canadian Journal of History, Sept. 23, 1978 (Folder 18, Box 11)
  - Ray, P. Orman. "The World-Wide Woman Suffrage Movement." Journal of Comparative Legislation and International Law, Oct. 1919 (Folder 19, Box 11)
  - JSM and the Old South (Folder 20, Box 11)
  - Women (Folder 21, Box 11)
  - Women's Rights Talk (Folder 22, Box 11)
  - Bibliography (Folder 23, Box 11)
  - Lists of Bibliography (Folder 24, Box 11)
  - JSM- Women in Factories (Folder 1, Box 12)
  - Madame Roland- Education of Women (Folder 2, Box 12)
  - Letter from Mill-Taylor collection and Blackwell letter from Johns Hopkins (Folder 3, Box 12)
  - Arsenic Bill (Folder 4, Box 12)
  - McCord, Louisa (Folder 5, Box 12)
  - Primarily, U.S (Folder 6, Box 12)
  - Carlyle- Masculine and Feminine (Folder 7, Box 12)
  - Spencer, Herbert (Folder 8, Box 12)
  - Votes for Women (Folder 9, Box 12)
  - Parliament, 1866 (Folder 10, Box 12)
  - Parliamentary Reform and Government (Folder 11, Box 12)
  - JSM in Parliament (Folder 12, Box 12)
  - [To] add-Section on British Control and Monthly Repository (Folder 13, Box 12)
  - Schwartz, Pedor. "New Political Economy of J.S. Mill." (Folder 14, Box 12)
  - Women's Votes (Folder 15, Box 12)
  - Population (Folder 16, Box 12)
  - Benthem, [Jeremy]. The Comparison to [Illegible] and Women (Folder 17, Box 12)
  - Louise Schyler Letler- M.T. Collection.[Illegible] Women's Suffrage (Folder 18, Box 12)
  - Stanton. et. al." History of Woman Suffrage." v.3, England (Folder 1, Box 13)
  - Barbara Bodiehon letter to Harriot Taylor, June 1866 (Mill Taylor Collection) (Folder 2, Box 13)
  - JSM and Women [ ] Parliament (Folder 3, Box 13)
  - The Ladies' Petition and JSM in Parliament (Folder 4, Box 13)
  - Women's Suffrage Journal, 1870- (Folder 5, Box 13)
  - Masculine and Feminine (Folder 6, Box 13)
  - "History of Women Suffrage"- vol.3, chapter LVIII. "Reminiscences" by Stanton (Folder 7, Box 13)
  - "The Rationale of Political Representation" by Bailey (Folder 8, Box 13)
  - JSM and Tocquevilie (Folder 9, Box 13)
  - "Criticism on Woman" (Folder 10, Box 13)
  - JSM- "Parties at the Ministry", "State of Society in America", and "Democracy in America" (Folder 11, Box 13)
  - An Outline of the Grievances of Women (Folder 12, Box 13)
  - [Sale of Arsenic Regulation Bill.] (Folder 13, Box 13)
  - British House of Commons and House of Lords Sessional Papers in the Library of Congress (Folder 14, Box 13)
  - JSM- Letter to Mr. Robertson about a Committee (Folder 15, Box 13)
  - Parkman, Francis (The Historian and the Law) (Folder 16, Box 13)
  - Johnson, Reverdy (Folder 17, Box 13)
  - Pankhurst, Sylvia (Folder 18, Box 13)
  - Subjection of Women (MIT Collection) (Folder 1, Box 14)
  - Cobbe, Francis Power. "Criminals, Idiots, Women, and Minors." (Folder 2, Box 14)
  - Mitchell, Juliet."Women and Equality." (Folder 3, Box 14)
  - Women and Economics (Folder 4, Box 14)
  - Jill, Roe."Modernization and Sexism: Recent Writings on Victorian Women." Victorian Studies, v.XX, no.2, 1977 (Folder 5, Box 14)
  - Spence, Catherine Helen. " Meeting with J.S. Mill and George Eliot." (Folder 6, Box 14)
  - Mc Gregor, O.R. "The Social Position of Women in England, 1850-1914: A Bibliography." British Journal of Sociology, v.6, 1955 (Folder 7, Box 14)
  - JSM- Speeches on Women's Suffrage (Folder 8, Box 14)
  - Germany and France (Folder 9, Box 14)
  - Analyses of Subjection of Women (Folder 10, Box 14)
  - JSM- Bibliography contributed to Mill Newsletter, June 1977 (Folder 11, Box 14)
  - Dixon, William Hepworth."Spiritual Wives." Westminster Review, April 1869 (Folder 12, Box 14)
  - Bostick, Theodore P. "Women's Suffrage, the Press, and the Reform Bill of 1867" and "The Press and the Launching of the Women's Suffrage Movement, 1866-1867." Victorian Periodicals Review, v.XII, Winter 1980 (Folder 13, Box 14)
  - Cobbe, Francis Power. "JSM on the Subjection of Women." Theological Review, 1869. Taylor, Henry. "Mr. Mill on the Subjection of Women." Fraser's Magazine, 1870 (Folder 14, Box 14)
  - Kornberg, Jacques. "Feminism and the Liberal Dialect: J.S.M. on Women's Rights." Canadian Historical Association, Historical Papers... 1947 (Folder 15, Box 14)
  - Whyte, Melvielle George. " Strong-Minded Women." Fraser's Magazine, v.68, Nov. 1863 (Folder 16, Box 14)
  - Menzies, Sutherland. "Political Women." (Folder 17, Box 14)
  - "Women and the Origins of the Liberalism."MAC: Political Studies, v.XXVII, June 1979 (Folder 18, Box 14)
  - On the Reception of Mary Wollstonecraft's.. (Folder 19, Box 14)
  - Priscilla Bell Wakefield Reflections.. (Folder 20, Box 14)
  - Mary Hays (Folder 21, Box 14)
  - Women's Education.. (Folder 22, Box 14)
  - Olcott- Women's Trade Union Movement, London 1874-1914 (Folder 23, Box 14)
  - JSM's and Gaskell's Opinions, from English Woman's Journal (Folder 24, Box 14)
  - Thackeray and Babbage (Folder 25, Box 14)
  - JSM- Maurice Cranston (Folder 26, Box 14)
  - J.S.Mill and the Working-Out of Empiricism- John Herman Randall, Jr (Folder 27, Box 14)
  - Poem about Dr. Johnfon (Folder 28, Box 14)
  - [Lady Dilke]- Finished copies (Folder 29, Box 14)
  - McCarthy, John."The Yelverton Case: Civil Legislation and Marriage." Victorian Studies, v.XIV, No.3, March 1971 (Folder 30, Box 14)
  - Tristan, Flora- Promenades Dans Londres (Folder 31, Box 14)
  - Flora Tristan (Folder 32, Box 14)
  - Index Cards (Box 15)
  - Index Cards (Box 16)
  - Index Cards (Box 17)
  - Index Cards (Box 18)
  - Index Cards (Box 19)
  - Index Cards (Box 20)
  - Index Cards (Box 21)
  - Index Cards (Box 22)
  - Feminism (Folder 1, Box 23)
  - Reform (Folder 2, Box 23)
  - Women's Disabilities Bill (Folder 3, Box 23)
  - Women's Suffrage (Folder 4, Box 23)
  - Bibliography (one page) (Folder 5, Box 23)
  - Women, 1868 (Folder 6, Box 23)
  - Unidentified (Folder 7, Box 23)
  - Research (Folder 8, Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 9, Box 23)
  - Translation (Folder 10, Box 23)
  - Index Cards (Box 24)